vegascreativesoftware.com 2019-06-23

# Privacy – VEGAS Creative Software

##  Part 1 - Introduction 

Thank you for your interest in our company. The protection of your data is important to us, so we have made it our mission to safeguard and protect your data and your rights in relation to data.

Personal data such as names, addresses, email addresses and telephone numbers are always processed in accordance with the General Data Protection Regulation, as well as with the country-specific data protection regulations relevant to us. This Privacy Policy contains information about the type of data that we collect, the extent to which we collect data and its purpose, and also about the rights that you have, provided that personal data has been collected or processed.

Throughout the Privacy Policy, we use various legal and technical terms. An explanation for these can be found in the section entitled "Definitions".

As the persons responsible for data processing, we have taken various different technical and organizational measures to ensure the personal data that we process is protected as completely as possible. Internet-based data transfer can however create security gaps, which means that absolute protection cannot be guaranteed. For this reason, you also have the option to communicate personal data to us through alternative methods, i.e. by telephone.

This Privacy Policy applies to personal data of our customers and suppliers, as well as of the visitors to our website.

The company which is responsible for data processing ("MAGIX" or "we") in accordance with the relevant Data Protection Laws (including the General Data Protection Regulation (Regulation (EU) 2016/679)) ("GDPR") is:

  * for [www.catooh.com](http://www.catooh.com/?l=en_UK_catooh) and the services which they operate:  
MAGIX Computer Products International Co.  
280 Greg St., Suite 10  
Reno, NV 89502-2272  
USA  
Website: [www.catooh.com](http://www.catooh.com/?l=en_UK_catooh)
  * for all other websites and services:  
MAGIX Software GmbH  
Quedlinburger Str. 1  
10589 Berlin  
Germany  
Email: [privacy@magix.net](mailto:privacy@magix.net)  
Websites: All websites and services of MAGIX Software GmbH 

In order to protect the interests of all persons affected by data processing, we have appointed a data protection officer. They can be contacted under the following details:

  * MAGIX Software GmbH  
Data protection officer  
Quedlinburger Str. 1  
10589 Berlin  
Germany  
Email: [privacy@magix.net](mailto:privacy@magix.net)

You can contact our data protection officer directly and at any time with any questions or concerns relating to data protection.

Important: Please note that this Privacy Policy may change from time to time. Please use this page to keep yourself up-to-date, as any possible future amendments will be made here.   
If you do not agree with a certain aspect of our Privacy Policy, you are entitled to certain legal rights, where applicable. These are described in the respective section below.

##  Part 2 - Summary:   
_Our Privacy Policy at a glance_

###  1\. What personal data do we collect? 

**User data:**  
If you are a customer of MAGIX, i.e. a user of our software, we must collect and use certain personal data in order to provide the right services to you, e.g.: (1) to deliver goods ordered, (2) to distribute updates and patches for your software, (3) to ensure that your software's licence is properly managed and to prevent product piracy, as well as (4) to provide you with information about offers which could be of interest to you.

A detailed description of which personal data we collect in this way can be found in the section entitled "Our Privacy Policy in detail".

**Supplier data:**   
We require certain information from our suppliers and providers in order to ensure that operations run smoothly. This includes taking contact details for the responsible person in your company in order to communicate with them. We also require further information such as your bank details, so that we can pay you for the services that you have provided (subject to contractual agreement).

A detailed description of the personal data that we collect about you can be found in the section entitled "Our Privacy Policy in detail".

**Visitors to the website:**  
We collect a limited amount of data from visitors to the website. This is to facilitate navigation on our websites and to better manage the services that we offer to you. The data we collect in this way comprises information about how you use our website and how often you access it.

Further information about the data that we collect about you when you visit our website can be found in the section entitled "Our Privacy Policy in detail".

###  2\. From whom is personal data collected? 

**User data:**  
We generally only collect your personal data directly from you.

**Supplier data:**  
We only collect your personal data directly from you in the course of working together with you.

**Visitors to the website:**  
When you visit the website, we automatically collect data using cookies in accordance with the cookie settings in your browser. We also collect data from you when you contact us via the websites, for example when you enter information into a contact form or use the chat function. Generally, we may collect certain data automatically as soon as you access our website or read or click on an email from us. More information about cookies and the choices that you can make relating to these can be found in the corresponding section in this Privacy Policy.

###  3\. Why we collect personal data and what we use it for 

**User data:**  
We collect and use information about our customers (i.e. users) primarily to make sure that the contractual agreement between you and MAGIX is properly implemented in order to ensure a smooth business relationship. For example, we require personal data in order to process sale and license agreements and so that we can send you the products that you have ordered. A user account, which stores personal data, is required to use our software. We require this in order to offer you multi-user licence management and to prevent product piracy. We also partly require personal data from you in order to provide you with our services (such as customer support) in the best possible way.

More information about how we use your personal data can be found in the section entitled "Our Privacy Policy in detail".

**Supplier data:**  
We use your personal data primarily for two reasons: The first is to make sure that the contractual agreement between you and MAGIX is properly implemented in order to ensure a smooth business relationship. The second is to ensure compliance with legal regulations.

More information about how we use your personal data can be found in the section entitled "Our Privacy Policy in detail".

**Visitors to the website:**  
We use your data to to facilitate navigation on our website, for example to display offers which we think will be of interest to you, or to save the contents of your shopping cart in the Store for your next visit.

More information about cookies, such as how we use them and which options are available to you can be found in in the section entitled "Our Privacy Policy in detail".

###  4\. Disclosure of personal data 

**User information**  
We transmit your personal data for the following reasons: (1) The first is to ensure that you receive the goods that you have ordered from us (i.e. transmission to a delivery service provider), (2) to payment service providers like PayPal, (3) to companies that dispatch the newsletter for us and/or (4) or to companies that provide us with support services.

An overview of the categories of recipient to whom your personal data can be given can be disclosed in the section entitled "Our Privacy Policy in detail".

**Supplier information**  
Unless you have specified otherwise, we can disclose your information to any of our group companies as well as associated third parties, e.g. service providers and organizations which we use and provide services for.

An overview of the categories of recipient to whom your personal data can be given can be disclosed in the section entitled "Our Privacy Policy in detail".

**Visitors to the website**  
Unless you specify otherwise, we can give your information to web analytics service providers, affiliate networks, marketing automation platforms and social media services, in order to ensure that you only receive appropriately targeted advertisements.

In general, we reserve the right to also transmit your data to other countries outside of the EU or EEA. In this case, we will however ensure a minimum level of data protection corresponding to the GDPR level of protection, through the appropriate arrangements.

###  5\. Duration for which we store personal data 

The criteria for the duration of storage for personal data is the respective legal retention period, after which the data will be deleted. In addition to this, we save the respective data only provided that they are still necessary for the fulfillment of a contract.

More information about our basic procedures relating to storage of personal data can be found in the section entitled "Our Privacy Policy in detail".

###  6\. Rights of the person affected – which rights do you have in relation to your personal data stored by us? 

Even if we already hold your personal data, you are entitled to various rights with regard to this information. If you would like to talk to us regarding this, please do not hesitate to contact us. We will make every effort to take care of your query as soon as possible and every case will be treated in accordance with applicable legal regulations. Please note that we may record our communication in order to better solve the issues raised by you.

Insofar as we save your personal data, certain legal rights apply (the "rights of the person affected"), which we will outline here. More information about individual rights can be found in the section entitled "Our Privacy Policy in detail".

  *  **Right to access information**  
At any time, you have the right to request us to confirm which information we have saved about you, and to request that this information be changed, updated, or deleted. We can then comply with your request. We also have the following options:  

    * We may ask you to confirm your identity, or request further information, and 
    * provided that this is permitted by law, we can decline your request. In this case, we will explain the reasons for doing so.
  *  **Right to objection:**  
If we use your data because we believe this is in our legitimate interests and you do not agree, you have the right to object. We will respond to your request within 30 days. In certain cases, we are entitled to extend this period. We will usually only disagree in very narrowly defined circumstances.
  *  **Right to revoke consent:**  
If we have obtained your consent to process your personal data for specific activities (for example, in order to send you advertisements), you can revoke this consent at any time.
  *  **Right to correction**  
You have the right to request that the personal data concerning you be immediately corrected or amended.
  *  **Right to deletion**  
In certain situations (for example, if we have unlawfully processed your data) you have the right to request us to delete your personal data. We will reply to your request within 30 days (in certain cases, we may however have the right to extend this period) and we will only disagree in very specific, narrowly defined circumstances – for example, if the data is absolutely necessary in order to continue to provide our services to you or to ensure the protection of our intellectual property. If we agree to your request, we will delete your data, but we will generally assume that you wish your name to be included in the list of persons that do not want to be contacted. In this way, we minimize the chance that you will be contacted in the future should your data be collected separately under other circumstances. If you do not wish this, please let us know.
  *  **Right to restrict processing**  
Instead of requesting deletion, you can also request from us that the processing of your data be restricted or blocked. We will also reply to this request within 30 days, except if we still need the data, for example in order to continue to provide our services to you or to ensure the protection of our intellectual property.
  *  **Right to data portability**  
Should you wish, you have the right to transfer your data from us to another person responsible. We will support you by transferring your data directly for you or by providing you with a copy in a standard machine-readable format.
  *  **Rights relating to automated decisions (profiling)**  
Under certain circumstances, you have the right not to be subject to a decision that has been based exclusively on automated processing and that will have legal effect against you. However, under certain circumstances we may have a legitimate interest in such automated decision-making.
  *  **Right of appeal to a regulatory body**  
You also have the right to lodge a complaint with a local regulatory body. Details about this can be found in the section entitled "Our Privacy Policy in detail".

###  7\. Use of cookies 

Our websites/web services use "cookies". Cookies are small text files that are saved on the hard drive of your PC (client) for a defined period.

Most cookies we use are deleted at the end of the browsing session (known as session cookies).  
Other cookies stay on your computer and allow us to recognize your computer on your next visit (permanent or persistent cookies).  
Cookies usually contain a "cookie ID". This is a pseudonymized date in the form of a unique cookie identification.  
It consists of a series of characters that can be used to associate websites and the servers with a specific Internet browser (client) in which the cookie is saved.

Cookies are generally distinguished into first and third party cookies.

First party cookies will only be assigned by the website that you are currently on (for example, the website under the domain magix.com).  
MAGIX uses first party cookies for essential website functions, like for storing website settings, restoring sessions and for securing your session data.   
For instance, this enables the MAGIX online Store to remember the items that a customer has placed in their shopping cart. However, most areas of our website essentially work without the use of cookies.

Within this process, access only occurs in impersonalized form and exclusively when you visit our website. Other websites cannot access this information.  
To ensure the data security of our visitors, it is necessary to allow first party cookies in order to use the MAGIX Service Center and MAGIX online Store.

Third party cookies are set by a third party provider that has been authorized by MAGIX, i.e. not by the actual website that you are currently viewing.

By using cookies, we can adjust our offers to best meet customer preferences and can make browsing our site as convenient as possible for you (advertising, conversion tracking and personalization).

In addition, we use third party providers in order to collect online statistics (analytics) as a basis for measuring the success of our advertising offers and subsequently improving them.  
Even when cookies from third party providers are used, data is only accessed in an anonymized form.

An overview of third parties on our websites can be found in the section entitled "Our Privacy Policy in detail".

All essential services from our website/web services essentially work without the use of third party cookies.

You can prevent cookies from being installed at any time by selecting the option "Do not accept cookies" in your browser. In addition, you can at any time delete cookies via your Internet browser or another software program. This can be done with any standard Internet browser.

##  Part 3: Our Privacy Policy in detail 

###  A. Detailed information about the processing of user and supplier data 

####  1\. What personal data do we collect? 

**User data:**  
We collect some data about our customers and users that we require to implement contracts and for license management and copy protection of our products. We therefore require your name, your email address and country of residence in order to create a user account, which is then used to activate software or content. The same information is collected when you register for our newsletter. We may also require further information from you (e.g. address, telephone number or date of birth), for instance for Store purchases, ordering of services, registering domains or ordering subscriptions. You may also provide us with further data - this is optional. The specific data collected depends on the form or input mask used, or as requested by our support staff over the phone.

If for any reason we require additional personal data from you, we will let you know.

We analyze the use of our products with Google Analytics. Here, specific computer data (including your computer's hardware key, processor name etc.) is used to create a pseudonymized profile, which collects usage data in order to improve our products. More information about this can be found in the section entitled "Our Privacy Policy in detail".

**Supplier data:**  
We only collect data about suppliers insofar as this is necessary, in order to maintain a streamlined business relationship. We collect data about our contact person in your organization, and some names, telephone numbers and email addresses. We also collect bank data for the purpose of making payments to you. We can also collect additional information that someone from your organization has shared with us. In certain circumstances, e.g. if you have been in contact with our financial department or billing department, our telephone calls with you may be recorded, regardless of local regulations and requirements.

####  2\. From whom is personal data collected? 

We generally only collect your personal data directly from you. We do not collect personal data from any other sources.

####  3\. Why we collect personal data and what we use it for 

**User data:  
In general, we use data on our users and customers in the following ways:**

**a) Advertising measures**  
We may send you information at regular intervals that we believe to be of interest to you, and also inform you of certain discounts and special offers to which you are entitled as a result of your business relationship with us.

We require your consent for some aspects of these activities that are not covered by our legitimate interests (in particular for data collection using cookies and direct marketing to you through our digital channels). According to the circumstance, we will ask for your explicit consent via "opt-in" or silent consent via "soft opt-in" (see below).

Consent via "soft opt-in" is a specific form of consent that applies if you have had business dealings with us before (e.g. you have ordered a product from us or registered a domain with us) and we may advertise other products or services within this context. For consent via "soft opt-in", we will consider your consent as provided, as long as you do not withdraw it.

You can revoke your consent at any time. More information about this can be found in the section that describes our Privacy Policy in detail.

Our advertising as a whole is based on entities that we consider to be especially helpful to our customers and users. However, we are aware that we do not always do things the right way for everybody. We may use your data to display you advertisements and other MAGIX content on other websites, e.g. Facebook. If you do not wish your data to be used in this way, please change the cookie settings in your browser, as described above. Even if you deactivate advertisement cookies, it's possible that you may continue to receive MAGIX advertisements. If this happens, it is because the advertisement is targeted towards an anonymous target group and not towards you specifically.

**b) Functionality of our products and security of our intellectual property rights**  
We are dependent on protecting our intellectual property rights, not least for the purposes of being able to offer you our products and services at their usual standard of quality and at attractive prices. In order to guarantee effective copy protection and enable you, depending on the product, to use our software on several computers, each installation of our software is linked to your user account, where certain data must be obligatorily saved (name, email address and country). It is only in this way that we can provide you with updates and patches for your software. To guarantee smooth operability of our products, you are therefore required to provide us with the above mentioned data

**c) Assertion, exercise or defence of legal rights**  
In unusual cases, we may also use your personal data in order to assert, exercise or defend legal rights.

We may use your personal data for these purposes if it corresponds with our legitimate interests. More information about what this means can be found in the section entitled "Our Privacy Policy in detail".

**Supplier data:**  
We will only use your information in order to conduct our business relationship with you in an optimal manner. To this end, we save your data in our database so that we can contact you in accordance with our agreement and can use your services. In unusual cases, we will use this data for the assertion, exercise or defence of legal rights.

####  4\. Disclosure of personal data 

We may share your personal data with the following categories of people in a variety of ways and for a variety of purposes, as appropriate and in accordance with local laws and regulations:

  * All company groups   

  * Tax authorities, audit authorities or other authorities, if we in good faith believe that we are required by law or other regulation to disclose such information (for example, because of a request from a tax authority or in connection with an anticipated legal dispute)  

  * External service providers that provide services in our name (including external email providers, auditors and accountants, technical support)  

  * Providers of external IT services and storage providers, if a corresponding arrangement (or similar assurance) exists  

  * Marketing technology platforms and suppliers

If in future we merge with or are acquired by another company (or should meaningful discussion about such a possibility take place), we may disclose your personal data to the (future) new company owners.

In general, we reserve the right to also transmit your data to other countries outside of the EU or EEA. In this case, we will however ensure a minimum level of data protection corresponding to the GDPR level of protection, through the appropriate arrangements.

####  5\. Duration for which we store personal data 

We process and save personal data solely for the duration necessary for achieving the purpose for which the data was stored, or as stipulated in laws and requirements set by the European directive and regulation provider or another legislator to which we are subject.

If the storage purpose ceases to apply or if a storage period prescribed by European directive and regulation provider or another competent legislator expires, the personal data will be deleted routinely and in accordance with the statutory provisions.

####  6\. How we protect your personal data 

We will adopt all reasonable and appropriate measures to protect the personal information we have stored from misuse, loss or unauthorized access. To this end, we have taken a range of technical and organizational measures. This includes measures to deal with any suspected breaches of data.

If you believe that your personal data has been misused or has been lost or has been accessed without authority, please inform us immediately. Our contact details can be found in Part 1 of this Privacy Policy.

###  B. Detailed information about the use of our website 

As mentioned above, we collect a limited amount of data from visitors to our websites in order to facilitate navigation of our websites and to better manage the services that we offer to you. You can use our websites without having to provide any personal data. In certain cases (e.g. Store orders, product activation etc.), processing of personal data may be required.

####  1\. General data and information collection 

Our websites collect a variety of general data and information each time one of their pages is loaded. This general data and information is saved to our server log files. Data that may be collected includes (1) browser types used and their versions, (2) operating system used, (3) the website from which an accessing system reaches our websites (what is known as a "referrer"), (4) subpages on our websites that are accessed by an accessing system, (5) date and time of visit to websites, (6) an Internet Protocol Address (IP address) and (7) any other similar data and information, that could serve as hazard prevention in the event of an attack on our IT systems.

No conclusions are drawn about the person concerned during the use of this general data and information. This information is required in order to (1) correctly transmit the content of our website, (2) optimize content of and advertising for our website, (3) guarantee the permanent functional operability of our information technology systems and technology for our website, and (4) in the event of a cyber attack, provide law enforcers with necessary information for prosecution. This anonymously collected data and information is therefore evaluated by us statistically and also with the aim of increasing data protection and data security in our company ultimately to ensure an optimum level of protection for the personal data processed by us. Anonymous server log file data are stored separately from all personal data provided by a person concerned.

####  2\. Registration on our website 

You can register your personal data on several of our websites, for instance by signing up to our newsletter or setting up a user account (e.g. through placing an order or by activating a MAGIX product). The specific personal data you submit to MAGIX is dependent on the type of input mask used for registration. The personal data submitted by the person concerned will be collected and stored for the sole purpose of internal use and purposes by MAGIX. We may arrange for disclosure to one or more contract processors, for example a parcel service provider, who also uses the personal data exclusively for an internal use that is attributable to us.

When registering on a MAGIX website, the IP address provided by your Internet service provider (ISP), date and time of registration will also be stored. This data is stored against the background that the misuse of our services can only be prevented in this manner and that this data may enable committed criminal offences to be investigated. In this respect, the storage of this data is necessary for MAGIX security reasons. This data will not be passed on to third parties unless required to do so by law or for the purpose of criminal prosecution.

Registration by voluntarily submitting data also enables us to offer you content or services that may only be offered to registered users due to to the nature of the offer. Registered users are free to modify personal data submitted during registration or have them deleted in entirety from our database.

Upon request, we will provide you at any time with information about which personal data we have stored about you. We will also correct or delete personal data upon your request or notification, as long as this does not conflict with any legal storage obligations. Our data protection officer is available as a contact person in this regard.

####  3\. Subscription to our newsletter 

Users have the option of subscribing to our newsletter via our websites. The specific personal data you submit to us when signing up to the newsletter is dependent on the type of input mask used.

You can only receive our newsletter if you (1) have a valid email address and (2) have registered for newsletter distribution.

When registering for the newsletter, the IP address provided by your Internet service provider (ISP), date and time of registration will also be stored. The collection of this data is necessary in order to track (potential) misuse of email addresses at a later point in time and therefore fulfils the purpose of legal protection for MAGIX.

Personal data stored within the scope of registration for newsletters will only be used in order to distribute our newsletter. This data will solely be transmitted to Selligent GmbH, Atelierstr. 12, 81671 Munich, to whom our newsletter distribution is contracted. In addition, no data is disclosed to third parties. You can cancel the use of your email address for advertising purposes at any time by clicking "Unsubscribe" at the bottom of the newsletter. You can at any time revoke the consent you have granted for storing personal data in order to receive our newsletter.

####  4\. Newsletter tracking 

The MAGIX Software GmbH newsletters contain what are known as tracking pixels. A tracking pixel is a miniature graphic embedded in emails in HTML format for the purposes of recording and analyzing log files. This enables us to conduct a statistic evaluation of the success or failure of our online marketing campaigns. On the basis of the technology used, we can recognize whether and when an email was opened by you and whether you clicked on the links within the email.

Data collected in this manner is stored and evaluated on our account by Selligent GmbH, Atelierstr. 12, 81671 Munich, in order to optimize newsletter distribution and modify the content of future newsletters further so that they match the interests of the person receiving the newsletter. Your data will not be disclosed to any third parties. You can revoke your declaration of consent for this, which you have granted separately, in this regard at any time. To do so, please contact our data protection officer.

####  5\. Contact options via the websites 

Our websites contains legally required information, which enables us to be contacted rapidly in a direct manner, for instance by email. If you contact us by email or via a contact form, the personal data submitted by you will be stored automatically. We store this voluntarily submitted personal data for purposes of handling or to communicate with you; we will not pass it on to third parties.

####  6\. Use and application of third party tools and services on our websites and applications 

We have integrated various third-party components on our websites. primarily for the purpose of optimizing your surfing experience and analyze user behavior on our websites. The following provides you with more information about this:

**a) Google**  
We use various services provided by Google, Inc. on our websites. The operator for the services of Google Remarketing is Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Pkwy, Mountain View, CA 94043-1351, USA. The following services are integrated into our websites:

  *  **Google Analytics**

MAGIX has integrated Google Analytics components into its websites.

The operator for Google Analytics components is Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Pkwy, Mountain View, CA 94043-1351, USA.

Google complies with the data protection provisions of the "Privacy Shield" agreement and is registered with the U.S. Department of Commerce's "Privacy Shield" program. <https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt000000001L5AAI>

For web analysis with Google Analytics, MAGIX uses an anonymization function, where Google shortens and anonymizes the IP address for the Internet connection of the person concerned.

Google Analytics is a web analytics service. Web analytics is the collection, organization and analysis of data on the behavior of visitors to websites. A web analytics service collects, among other things, data on which websites a person concerned came to a website from ("referrer" URLs), which subpages of the websites were accessed or how often and for how long a website was viewed. These web analysis metrics are mainly used as a data basis for optimizing the functions and contents of a website.

Google Analytics sets a cookie on the computer of the person concerned. The definition of cookies has been provided above. Using cookies enables Google to analyze the use of our websites. Each time a user visits one of the pages of the websites that are operated by MAGIX and upon which Google Analytics components are embedded, the Internet browser on the computer of the person concerned is automatically prompted by the Google Analytics components to transmit data to Google for the purpose of online analysis. As part of this technical procedure, Google obtains knowledge of personal data, such as the IP address of the person concerned, which enables Google to trace the origin of the visitors and their behavior on the site, among other things.

Cookies are used to store personal information, such as access time, the location from which access came and the frequency of visits to our websites by the person concerned. For every visit to our websites, this personal data, including the IP address of the Internet connection used by the person concerned, will be transferred to Google in the United States of America. This personal data will be stored by Google in the United States of America. Google may disclose the personal data collected through this technical process to third parties.

You can prevent the setting of cookies by our websites, as described above, at any time via the settings for your Internet browser and thus permanently object to the setting of cookies. This Internet browser setting will also prevent Google from setting a cookie on the computer of the person concerned. In addition, cookies that have already been set by Google Analytics can be deleted via your Internet browser or another software program.

Furthermore, the person concerned has the option to object to and prevent the recording of data on the use of these websites by Google Analytics and the processing of this data by Google. To do so, the person concerned must download and install a browser add-on under the link <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout> . This browser add-on communicates to Google Analytics via JavaScript that data and information regarding visitors to websites may not be transferred to Google Analytics. The installation of the browser add-on will be considered as an objection by Google. If the information technology system of the person concerned is at a later point in time deleted, formatted or reinstalled, the person concerned must reinstall the browser add-on in order to deactivate Google Analytics. If the browser add-on is uninstalled or deactivated by the person concerned or another person under their authority, it is possible to reinstall or reactivate the browser add-on.

Further information and the Google Analytics Privacy Policy can be viewed at  <https://www.google.de/intl/de/policies/privacy/> and  
at <http://www.google.com/intl/de/analytics/privacyoverview.html> .

  *  **Google Remarketing**

Google Remarketing is a feature of Google AdWords that allows us to display advertisements to Internet users who have previously spent time on our websites. In this way we can create user-related advertising and display advertisements relevant to you, for instance through the Google advertising network.

Google Remarketing uses cookies. This enables Google to recognize a visitor to our websites if they subsequently access websites that are also members of the Google advertising network. Upon each visit to a website where Google Remarketing has been integrated, Google automatically identifies the Internet browser of the person concerned. As part of this technical process, Google obtains knowledge of personal data, such as the IP address or surfing behavior of the user, which Google uses to display relevant advertising or advertising of interest to the user, among other things.

Cookies are used to store personal data, for instance data on the websites you visit. For every visit to our websites, therefore, personal data including the IP address of the Internet connection you use will be transferred to Google in the United States of America. This personal data will be stored by Google in the United States of America. Google may disclose the personal data collected through this technical process to third parties.

You can prevent the setting of cookies by our websites, as described above, at any time via the settings for your Internet browser and thus permanently object to the setting of cookies. This Internet browser setting will also prevent Google from setting a cookie on the computer of the person concerned. In addition, cookies that have already been set by Google Analytics can be deleted via your Internet browser or another software program.

You can also choose not to receive interest-based advertising from Google. To do this you need to go to [www.google.de/settings/ads](https://www.google.de/settings/ads) on each of the Internet browsers you use and modify the settings there.

Further information and the Google Privacy Policy can be viewed at [https://www.google.de/intl/de/policies/privacy/](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en-GB&gl=de).

  *  **Google AdWords**

Google AdWords is an Internet advertising service that permits advertisers to place ads in Google search engine results and in the Google advertising network. Google AdWords enables advertisers to set predefined keywords: an advertisement will be displayed in Google search results only if the user's search engine results are relevant to the keywords. Within the Google advertising network, advertisements are distributed to thematically relevant websites by means of an automatic algorithm and predefined keywords.

Google AdWords are used for the advertisement of our websites through the placement of interest-based advertisements on websites of other companies and in the search engines results for search engine Google, as well as the placement of third party advertisements on our website.

Should a person arrive at our website via a Google advertisement, a "conversion cookie" will be placed on the computer of that user by Google. The definition of cookies has been provided above. A conversion cookie loses its validity after a limited period of time and is not used to identify the person concerned. If the cookie has not yet expired, the conversion cookie is used to determine whether certain subpages, such as the shopping basket of an online shop system, have been accessed on our website. The conversion cookie enables both us and Google to track whether a person who has placed an ad on our website has generated revenue, that is, whether they have completed or canceled a purchase of goods.

The data and information obtained through the use of conversion cookies are used by Google to create statistics about visits to our website. These visitor statistics are in turn used by us to determine the total number of users who arrived at our website via AdWords advertisements, as well as the success rate of the corresponding AdWord advertisement, and to optimize our AdWords advertisements in the future. Neither our company nor the other clients of Google AdWords receive information from Google which could identify the person concerned.

By means of conversion cookies, personal data is saved, for example the websites that have been visited by the person concerned. For every visit to our websites, therefore, personal data including the IP address of the Internet connection of the person concerned will be transmitted to Google in the United States of America. This personal data will be stored by Google in the United States of America. Google may disclose the personal data collected through this technical process to third parties.

You can prevent the setting of cookies by our websites, as described above, at any time via the settings for your Internet browser and thus permanently object to the setting of cookies. This Internet browser setting will also prevent Google from setting a conversion cookie on the computer of the person concerned. In addition, cookies that have already been set by Google AdWords can be deleted via your Internet browser or another software program.

In addition, the person concerned can choose not to receive interest-based advertising from Google. To do this you need to go to [www.google.de/settings/ads](https://www.google.de/settings/ads) on each of the Internet browsers you use and modify the settings there.

Further information and the Google Privacy Policy can be viewed at [https://www.google.de/intl/de/policies/privacy/](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en-GB&gl=de).

**b) Affiliate Networks**

We have integrated components of the following affiliate networks into our website for the purpose of affiliate marketing:

affilinet GmbH  
Sapporobogen 6-8  
80637 Munich  
Germany

AWIN AG  
Eichhornstraße 3  
10785 Berlin  
Germany

Firstlead GmbH  
Rosenfelder Str. 15-16  
10315 Berlin  
Germany

TradeTracker Deutschland GmbH  
Uhlandstraße 26  
22085 Hamburg  
Germany

MAGIX & VEGAS Creative Software Affiliate Program

MAGIX Software GmbH  
Quedlinburger Str. 1  
10589 Berlin  
Germany

Rakuten Marketing (formerly Linkshare)

Rakuten Marketing LLC  
215 Park Ave. South, 9th Floor  
New York, NY 10003, USA

Effiliation  
80, Rue Taitbout  
75009 Paris  
Frankreich

CJ Affiliate by Conversant  (formerly Commission Junction)

Conversant Deutschland GmbH  
Rosenheimer Straße 145 e-f  
81671 Munich  
Germany

Affiliate marketing is a web-based distribution system, which allows commercial operators of websites, merchants or advertisers, to place advertisements, which are mostly compensated per click or sales commission, on third party websites (partners), which are also called affiliates or publishers. The merchant provides advertising media over an affiliate network such as a banner advertisement or a suitable media for Internet advertisement, which is subsequently linked and advertised by an affiliate on their own websites or other such channel, such as social media or email marketing.

The respective affiliate network places a cookie on your computer ("affiliate cookie"). The definition of cookies has been provided above. The affiliate cookie does not save any personal data. Only the identification number of the affiliate is saved, that is, the partner who is referring a potential customer, as well as a reference number for the website visitor and the advertising media clicked. This data is stored for the purpose of processing commission payments between a merchant and the affiliate, which is processed via the affiliate network.

You can prevent the setting of cookies by our websites, as described above, at any time via the settings for your Internet browser and thus permanently object to the setting of cookies. This Internet browser setting will also prevent an affiliate network from setting a cookie on your computer. Moreover, cookies can be deleted from an affiliate network via your Internet browser or another software programs at any time.

**c) Hotjar**

MAGIX utilizes the software "Hotjar" (Hotjar Ltd, Level 2 St Julians Business Centre, 3, Elia Zammit Street St Julians STJ 1000, Malta, EU) for user experience optimization of our websites. Hotjar enables us to assess user behavior (e.g. mouse movement, clicks, scrolling) on our website. For this purpose, Hotjar uses cookies on the system of website visitors and can collection technical information (e.g. browser information, operating system, duration of visit, etc.). More information on the Hotjar privacy policy and opt-out options can be found here: <https://www.hotjar.com/privacy>.

**d) Dynamic Yield**

Our website uses Dynamic Yield, a service provided by Dynamic Yield Ltd., Highlands House, Basingstoke Road, Spencers Wood, Reading, Berkshire, England RG7 1NT ([https://www.dynamicyield.com](https://www.dynamicyield.com/)).

Using the Dynamic Yield tool, we carry out measures
